Guide to the Samuel Roth papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series IV: Publishing 1919-1974
  - IV.1. Subseries: Promotional Materials, 1919-1960s
    - American Aphrodite
      - "Aphrodite Material," Undated (Box 39, Folder 10)
      - Art, Undated (Box 39, Folder 11)
      - Cover Negative and Photo, Undated (Box 39, Folder 12)
      - Nudes, 1950s (Box 39, Folder 13)
      - Oversize, 1950s (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - Bumarap, Undated (Box 39, Folder 14)
    - Bumarap, 1940s-1950s (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - The Crippled Giant, 1950 (Box 39, Folder 15)
    - The Crippled Giant, 1950 (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - Diaitis: Cancer Prevention and Cure, 1960s (Box 39, Folder 16)
    - Drink and Stay Sober and Skin-Edge Razors, 1950s (Box 53, Folder 17)
    - Drink and Stay Sober, Undated (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - The Education of a French Model, 1950s (Box 39, Folder 18)
    - The Education of a French Model, Undated (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - Everybody's Pleasure, Undated (Box 39, Folder 19)
    - Everybody's Pleasure, 1960s (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - Fantazius Mallare, Undated (Box 53, Folder 5)
    - Forlorn Sunset, Undated (Box 39, Folder 20)
    - Golden Treasury of the World's Wit and Wisdom, Undated (Box 48, Folder 8)
    - Good Times, 1950s-1960s (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - I Was Hitler's Doctor, 1940s-1950s (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - I Was Hitler's Doctor, 1940s (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - I was Hitler's Doctor, 1940s-1950s (Box 48, Folder 9)
    - Julius Caesar, Undated (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - Jews Must Live for Christmas Gifts, 1964 (found in re-edition of Jews Must Live) (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Living Dolls, Undated (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - Living Dolls, 1950s (Box 48, Folder 10)
    - My Friend Yeshea, 1960s (Box 40, Folder 5)
    - My Friend Yeshea, Undated (Box 48, Folder 11)
    - My Life with Jesus --Promotional Drafts, Undated (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - My Sister and I, 1950s (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - My Sister and I, 1950s (Box 53, Folder 8)
    - My Sister and I, 1950s (Box 48, Folder 12)
    - The Natural History of David Zorn, Undated (Box 53, Folder 9)
    - The Nude in the French Theatre, Undated (Box 48, Folder 13)
    - Papier-mâché plate of "Unusual Classics," 1953 (Box 53, Folder 10)
    - Parisian Nights, Undated (Box 53, Folder 11)
    - Parisian Nights, Undated (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - The Peephole of the Present, 1940s (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - The Peep-Hole of the Present, 1940s (Box 48, Folder 13)
    - Picasso for Children, 1962 (Box 40, Folder 10)
    - Picasso for Children, 1960s (Box 48, Folder 14)
    - Poetry Book Shop and The Lyric, 1919-1920 (Box 40, Folder 11)
    - Sex Can Be Fun As Well as Useful & Educational, 1960s (Box 53, Folder 12)
    - The Sexual Conduct of Men & Women, 1950s (Box 40, Folder 12)
    - Shopping for Life & Pleasure, 1961, Undated (Box 40, Folder 13)
    - Shopping for Life & Pleasure, Undated (Box 48, Folder 15)
    - Skin-Edge Micro-Blades, Undated (Box 40, Folder 14)
    - Tina and Jimmy Learn How They Were Born, 1948-1949, Undated (Box 40, Folder 15)
    - Tina & Jimmy Learn How They Were Born, 1960s (Box 48, Folder 16)
    - Unusual Books, 1950s, Undated (Box 40, Folder 16)
    - Unusual Books --Printing Block, Undated (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Violations of the Child Marilyn Monroe, 1960s (Box 40, Folder 17)
    - Yankee Trader, Undated (Box 48, Folder 17)
    - You Scratch My Back, Undated (Box 53, Folder 13)
  - IV.2. Subseries: Business Files and Materials, 1930-1974 (Box 41)
    This subseries contains mostly book contracts, with some receipts, business certificates, financial documents, copyright registrations, and newspaper clippings regarding books published by various Roth imprints. In rare cases, some correspondence accompanies the book contract. In addition, photographs, printing blocks, and documents related to Roth's publishing endeavors can be found here. The material is arranged alphabetically.
    - Address Books, 1930s-1950s, (4 Folders) (Box 41, Folder 1 to 4)
    - "After Two Years of Retirement," Undated (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - "Bibliography of E. Phillips Oppenheim," 1966 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Book Jacket Design-- This Northern Country, 1940s (Box 48, Folder 18)
    - "Book Leads Inc"--Ledger, 1948-1949 (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - Business Certificates, 1941-1966 (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - "Business for Sale," 1958 (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - Certificates of Dissolution, 1947-1950 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Clippings
      - Editions of Thunder: The White Man's Viewpoint, 1964-1966 (Includes Ads for Jews Must Live) (Box 42, Folder 2)
      - Fritz Duquesne, 1930s (Box 42, Folder 3)
      - Marilyn Monroe, 1962 (Box 42, Folder 4)
      - My Uncle Benjamin, 1941 (Box 42, Folder 5)
      - Reviews of Bumarap and Halfway, 1947 (Box 42, Folder 6)
      - Reviews of Europe, 1920 (Box 42, Folder 7)
      - Reviews of Herbert Hoover Book, 1933 (Box 42, Folder 8)
      - Reviews of Songs Out of Season and Jews Must Live, 1931-1934 (Box 42, Folder 9)
      - Reviews of Various Titles, 1952, 1970, 1972 (Box 42, Folder 10)
      - "What Jesus Really Looked Like," by Samuel Roth, 1955 (Box 42, Folder 11)
    - "The Colonial Press Diary," 1957 (Box 42, Folder 12)
    - Contracts, 1930s-1950s, (3 Folders) (Box 42, Folder 13 to 15)
    - Copyright
      - Count Me Among the Missing, 1974
      - Inside Hitler--Letter of Authentication, 1966
      - My Friend Yeshea, 1962, 1967
      - My Sister and I, 1952
    - Cover Design-- The Natural History of David Zorn, Undated (Box 42, Folder 21)
    - Dust Jacket-- A Journey With Love, Undated (Box 42, Folder 22)
    - Financial
      - Advertising Payments, 1968 (Box 43, Folder 1)
      - Budget Notes, 1948 1950s (Box 43, Folder 3)
      - Ledger of Expenses, 1933 (Box 43, Folder 4)
      - Receipts
        - 1946-1966 (Box 43, Folder 5)
        - Purchase Of Samuel Roth's Publishing Business, 1970 (Box 43, Folder 6)
        - Rental Agreement, 1957 (Box 43, Folder 7)
      - Royalty Statements, 1960, 1965 (Box 43, Folder 8)
      - Seven Sirens Press
        - Bank Statements, 1961-1970, (3 Folders) (Box 43, Folder 9 to 11)
        - Bills, 1950s-1970s, (2 Folders) (Box 43, Folder 12 to 13)
        - Checks, 1956-1970, (2 Folders) (Box 51, Folder 3 to 4)
        - Ledger of Expenses, 1950s-1960s (Includes Clippings of Marilyn Monroe) (Box 43, Folder 14)
        - Mutual Payroll Book, 1960s (Box 43, Folder 15)
        - Taxes, 1960s (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Letterhead--Assorted, Undated (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - List of Authors and Editors, Undated (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Loft Leases, 1942, 1961, 1965, 1967 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - "Lord Alfred Douglas Materials," 1930s (Portraits and Correspondence) (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - MS RECORDS Notebook, 1968 (with correspondence) (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - "Partial List of Good Times Writers and Artists, Undated (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - Permission to do Business as Philosophical Book Club, 1945 (Box 44, Folder 9)
    - Photographs and Negatives
      - Baker, Denys Val, Undated (Box 44, Folder 10)
      - Bodenheim, Maxwell, 1948 (Box 44, Folder 11)
      - Heatter, Basil, Undated (Box 44, Folder 12)
      - John, Angelo P., Undated (Box 44, Folder 13)
      - Monroe, Marilyn, 1950s-1960s (Box 44, Folder 14)
      - Nietzsche, Elizabeth, Undated (Box 44, Folder 15)
      - Reiser, Oliver, 1940s (Box 44, Folder 16)
      - Roth, Samuel, 1940s (for Vanity Fair) (Box 44, Folder 17)
      - Wagner, Cossima, Undated (Box 44, Folder 18)
    - Printing Blocks, Undated (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Printing Blocks and Metal Plate of The World Sensorium, Undated (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - Record of Ads Placed, 1960s (Box 44, Folder 19)
  - IV.3. Subseries: American Aphrodite, 1950s (Box 45)
    This subseries contains stories and essays clipped from issues of American Aphrodite: A Quarterly for the Fancy Free. The material has been arranged alphabetically by title, with the name of the author, when known, indicated.
    - "The Amores of P. Ovidius Naso," 1950s (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - "The Duet," by H.E. Bates, 1950s (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - "The Dutch Lover," 1952 (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - "Forbidden Books," 1950s (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - "The Greater Omnibus of Private Books," by H.A. Manhood, 1950s (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - "The Half 'n Half Woman," 1950s (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - The Horn Book, by Gershon Legman, 1950s (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - "The Kiss to the Leper," by François Mauriac, 1950s (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - "Laughter in Hell" and Other Poems by George Sylvester Viereck, 1950s (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - Lexicon of Love: A Guide to the Affections and Disaffections of Mankind, by Samuel Roth, 1950s (Box 45, Folder 10)
    - "The Life and Death of St. Herbault" by Patrick Kirwan, 1950s (Box 45, Folder 11)
    - "Maiden's Fury: A Short Novel on the Attempted Seduction of an Ugly Woman," by H.A. Manhood, 1950s (Box 45, Folder 12)
    - "Midnight… Place Pigalle" by Maurice Dekobra, 1950s (Box 45, Folder 13)
    - "Mrs. Edmond's Life," by H.E. Bates, 1950s (Box 45, Folder 14)
    - "The Odalisque," with "Was Shakespeare a Man or a Woman?" by Viereck, 1950s (Box 45, Folder 15)
    - "One of Norah's Early Days," by Rhys Davies, 1950s (Box 45, Folder 16)
    - "A Passion Before Death," by James Hanley, and "The Penultimate Adventure" by Norman Davey, 1950s (Box 45, Folder 17)
    - "Restless Night…" and "The Anatomy of Female Itch," 1951 (Box 45, Folder 18)
    - "Sexual Secrets of the Orient," 1950s. (Box 45, Folder 19)
    - "The Strange Confession of Monsieur Mountcairn: A Practising Homosexual," 1950s (Box 45, Folder 20)
    - "Sun," Unexpurgated, by D.H. Lawrence, 1950s (Box 45, Folder 21)
    - "The Twilight of the Nymphs" by Pierre Louÿs, 1951 (Box 45, Folder 22)
    - "The Wife of King Candaules," by Theophile Gautier, 1950s (Box 45, Folder 24)
- Series V: Personal, 1915-1994
  This small series comprises documents such as family photographs, financial materials including bank statements and tax-related documents, wills and testaments, funeral matters, and a framed print of Samuel Roth's village of birth in rural Poland.
  - General
    - Adelaide Kugel Roth, 1943 1960s-1990s, Undated (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Samuel Roth, 1970s, Undated (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Calendar, 1963 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Children's Drawings, Undated (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Claim for Disability Benefits, 1960 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Clippings, 1950s-1970s (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Death Certificates, 1974-1977 (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Financial
    - Banking, 1960s-1970, 1987 (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - Car Insurance, 1970 (Box 46, Folder 9)
    - Taxes, 1951-1970 (2 of 3 Folders) (Box 46, Folder 10)
    - Taxes, 1951-1970 (1 of 3 Folders) (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Freedom of Information Act, FBI Files, Undated, (2 Folders) (Box 47, Folder 2 to 3)
  - Health-Related, 1960s, Undated (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - "A Map of the Village of Nuszcze in the Province of Tarnopol Poland," 1952 (Framed Art) (Box 1)
  - Marriage Certificate--Samuel and Pauline Roth, 1985 (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Photographs
    - "Pearl Gray," 1922 (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - Picture-Postcards--Samuel Roth and Frank Tannenbaum, 1915 (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - Police Raid, 1955 (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - Roth Family, 1930s, Undated (Box 47, Folder 9)
    - Samuel Roth, 1955 (with note) (Box 47, Folder 10)
    - Samuel Roth and Poetry Book Shop, 1920s, 1940s (Box 47, Folder 11)
  - Rent-related, 1950s-1960s (Box 47, Folder 12)
  - Scrapbooks
    - Clippings--Mostly Nietzsche and Mitchell, 1940s-1950s (Box 53, Folder 14)
    - Clippings--Reviews, Letters, 1930s-1950s, (2 Folders) (Box 53, Folder 15 to 16)
  - Wills
    - Joseph Roth, 1933 (with note) (Box 47, Folder 13)
    - Pauline Roth, 1969-1970s (Box 47, Folder 14)
    - Samuel and Pauline Roth, 1949-1969 (Box 47, Folder 15)
    - Samuel Roth, 1974 (Box 47, Folder 16)
      (with Death Certificate and Obituary)